（春野はるのサクラ）だああ～！
（うずまきナルト）おっ
あっ
We're too late...
（はたけカカシ）遅かったか
Sasori...
（チヨ）サソリ…
Neji...
（マイト･ガイ）ネジ
俺の状況は見えているか？
Can you see what's happening
to me here?
（日向ひゅうがネジ）ああ
Yeah...
The same thing is happening here.
こっちも同じ状況だ
（ガイ）テンテン そっちは？
Tenten, what about you?
（テンテン）たぶん同じ状況
It's probably...
the same here, too.
Lee!
（ガイ）リー？
（ロック･リー）
札を剥がしたとたんに
森の中に怪しい影が出現しました
A strange shadow appeared in the forest
as soon as I removed the tag.
I thought so...
やはり そうか
（ネジ）カカシ班は
予定どおり中に侵入した
Team Kakashi has infiltrated
just as planned.
なんなの？ これ
What is... this...?
It's probably an enemy trap.
恐らく敵のトラップでしょう
I see...
なるほど
そういうわけね
So that's what this is about.
相手にとって不足なしです
I find you a worthy opponent.
♪～
tooku de kikoeru koe wo hinto ni
A voice heard in the distance gives me a hint.
hitori mata hitori tachiagaru doushi
One by one like-minded people are standing up.
kurikaesu dake no fudan doori kutsugaesu
Lets overturn all the everyday, monotonous things.
junbi iize are you ready
I'm ready, are you ready?
karadajuu furuwasu shindou ni hageshiku uchinarase yo stomping
A shiver spreads through my body, violently ringing stomping.
taezu tsuki ugokasu call me
Constantly stirring in me, it calls me.
kawarazu yuru ga nutsukamu story come on
Catching that unchanging, never wavering story, Come on!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Hold up your fingers and count down.
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
hey yo whoa tashou no risuku wa kakugo desho
Are you ready for a few risks?
nanka korundatte tatsu get it on
You have to get up no matter how many times you fall. (Get it on!)
nare ai ja nai ze kami hitoe no sesshon
It's not some conspiracy, just a paper-thin session
irikunda kanjou kidzukiageta kesshou
The pent up feelings turn into a crystal.
wakiagaru kansei ga yuuki tonaru
The rising cheers will become your courage.
tachiagareba ima ijou kurushimi tomonau
So stand up now, no matter how much pain you feel.
soredemo saigo wa kitto warau
But in the end I'm sure you'll laugh.
subete sarau shouri to kansei
Everything will be swept away in victory and cheer.
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
～♪
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Hold up your fingers and count down.
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
Traps Activate!
Team Guy's Enemies
くっ… てめえ
You bastard...!
くっ…
どこ座ってんだよ！
Where do you think you're sitting?!
（デイダラ）フッ
間違いないな うん
No doubt about it...
あいつが人柱力だ
He's the Jinchuriki.
“最初に大声で
どなってくるヤツ”か…
"The first one to yell and
scream at you", huh?
イタチのヤツ
特徴 教えんのうめえな うん
Itachi's pretty good
at describing people.
（チヨ）サソリ…
Sasori...
（ナルト）我愛羅があら！
Gaara!
そんなところで
何 のんきに寝てんだってばよ
What're you doing sleeping leisurely
in a place like that?!
Stand up!
立てよ
Gaara!
我愛羅！
おい 我愛羅 聞いてんのか？
Hey! Gaara! Are you listening?!
いいかげんにしろよ！
Knock it off!
（カカシ）やめろ ナルト！
（ナルト）くっ…
That's enough, Naruto!
You should know...
（カカシ）分かってるはずだ
（ナルト）くっ…
そうそう 分かってんだろ？
That's right. You know, don't you?
とっくに死んでるってな うん？
That he's already long dead.
（サソリ）ほ～
Oh...
確かに人柱力だな うん
He's definitely... the Jinchuriki.
（サクラ）あっ
（ナルト）返せ
Give him back...
我愛羅を返せ この野郎が！
Give Gaara back!
You jerks!
はっ！
（カカシ）落ち着け
考えなしに突っ込めば全滅だ
Calm down...
If you charge ahead without thinking,
we'll be annihilated.
くっ…
忍の活動はスリーマンセル
もしくはフォーマンセルが基本だ
A Shinobi usually operates
in a three-man squad
or a four-man squad.
（ネジ）だが 五封結界を破るには
最低でも５人は必要
But at least five people are required
to destroy a Five-Seal Barrier.
１班だけでは
破ることができない
It can't be destroyed with
just one team.
どうしても もう１班の到着を
待たなければならない
You'd have to wait for
another team to arrive.
五封結界を張ったというだけで
Just putting up a Five-Seal Barrier
should serve as a means for stalling...
すでに足止めに
なっているわけですね
（ガイ）さらに結界が外されても
In addition, it's configured
so that a trap activates when
the barrier is removed.
トラップが発動する
仕組みになっている
Namely, a copy of the person who
removes the tag appears nearby.
（ネジ）すなわち札を剥がした者の
コピーが近くに現れ
はあっ
They're preventing us from making
our way through the barrier, huh?
結界への侵入を阻むってわけね
（リー）つまり
自分自身を倒さぬ限り
In other words...
we can't go back up to
Naruto and the others
ナルト君たちの援護には行けない
ということですか？
unless we defeat ourselves...
Is that how this works?
（ガイ）そのとおりだ リーよ
Exactly, Lee.
フォーマンセルをばらして
１人ずつにし
They break up the four-man squad
and separate us individually.
結界には周到に
保険までかけてるとは
And even taking precaution by placing
a back-up on the barrier...
大したやつらだ
They're quite impressive.
でも 感心ばかりも
してられないのよね
But... we can't just sit here
acting impressed.
いざ 勝負です
Now, let's fight!
ああーっ！
あっ…
ああっ
さすがは俺の偽物 やるな
I'd expect no less from my fake!
He's pretty good.
（ネジ）あっ
They don't just look the same...
（ネジ）姿だけでなく力も同じか
They've got the same power too, huh...?
はあっ！
ハア ハア…
装備も同じと考えていいわね
We should consider them as having
the same weapons too, huh...?
（リー）何から何まで
同じというわけですか
So basically everything about them
is the same, huh?
This makes them even
more worthwhile opponents, eh?!
ますます 戦い甲斐がありますね
くっ うう…
うん？ どうした サソリの旦那
What is it, Sasori my man?
（サソリ）そいつは俺が預かる
I'll take him.
（デイダラ）はっ？
（サソリ）どうやら あの人柱力は
こいつを取り返したいらしいからな
It seems that Jinchuriki wants
to take him back, so...
うん そうみたいだな
It seems so.
（カカシ）どうやら
左側が単身 砂に乗り込み...
It appears the guy on the left
is the one who infiltrated
the Sand alone and took Gaara.
風影様を連れ去った
ヤツのようだな
Which means this guy's...
すると こっちが
カンクロウ君に
深手を負わせた傀儡くぐつ師
the Puppet Master who
seriously injured Kankuro...
Her grandson Sasori, huh?
彼女の孫のサソリか
My man...
（デイダラ）旦那？
（サソリ）うん？
これを言ったら
たぶん旦那は怒るだろうけどよ
You'll probably get mad if I say this...
But I'll take care
of that Jinchuriki.
あの人柱力は
おいらがやる うん
（サソリ）んっ…
Our mission is one Jinchuriki each.
ノルマは１人１匹だろうが
図に乗るなよ デイダラ
Don't be getting all full
of yourself, Deidara...
（デイダラ）芸術家ってのは
より強い刺激を求めていねえと
An artist's passion starts to dull
unless they seek
greater stimulation, my man...
感情が鈍っちまうもん
なんすよ 旦那
九尾の人柱力は
なかなかに強いって噂だしな うん
The rumor is the Nine-Tailed Jinchuriki
is quite powerful.
He's an opponent suitable for my art.
おいらの芸術に
ふさわしい相手だ うん
What? You're calling those explosions
of yours art?
（サソリ）なんだ？
あの爆発が芸術だってのか
Art is something that beautifully remains...
芸術ってのは長く美しく
あとあとまで残っていくもの
extensively into the distant future.
Eternal beauty is art!
永久の美こそが芸術だ
Eternal beauty... is art?
（デイダラ）永久の美が芸術？
I do respect you as
a fellow craftsman, my man.
（デイダラ）同じモノづくりとして
旦那 あんたは尊敬するが
But art is a fleeting moment of beauty
that vanishes gloriously.
芸術ってのは...
美しく儚く散っていく
一瞬の美をいうんだよ うん
What did you say...?
（サソリ）なんだと？
Wh-What's up with... these guys?
な… なんなの？ こいつら
Deidara, it seems you don't
understand what true art is...
（サソリ）デイダラ
お前は本当の芸術ってもんが
分かってないようだな
You're the one
who doesn't understand.
（デイダラ）
それは旦那のほうだろ うん？
You jerks...!
（ナルト）てめえら…
（サソリ）いいや
永久の美こそ本当の芸術だ
No! Eternal beauty is true art.
Don't be a fool.
Art is an instant of beauty.
（デイダラ）バカ言っちゃいけねえ
芸術は 一瞬の美だ
（ナルト）ふざけやがって！
Knock it off!
あっ
（サソリ）てめえは
俺を怒らせてえのか？
Do you want to make me angry?
I just told you...
だから
It would probably make
you angry, didn't I...?
“たぶん怒るだろうけど”って
さっき言ったろうが うん？
（サソリ）俺を怒らせると
どういうことになるか...
You know what happens
when I get angry, don't you?
分かってんだろうな
He blocked the shuriken
without looking at all...
（サクラ）少しも見ずに手裏剣を…
He's just as good with
the Puppet Master technique
（チヨ）やはり 傀儡さばきは
昔のままじゃな
as he always was.
How about it, Deidara?
（サソリ）どうなんだ？ デイダラ
（デイダラ）フッ
Art to me is...
おいらにとっての芸術とは…
explosiveness itself!
爆発 そのものだ
うん！
ああ…
It's a far cry from
your silly puppet shows!
旦那のびっくり人形劇とは
わけが違うぜ うん
（サソリ）チッ
See you around, my man!
じゃあな 旦那
Make sure you follow me,
Nine-Tailed Jinchuriki...
（デイダラ）ちゃんとついてこいよ
九尾の人柱力
くっ… えいっ
（カカシ）はっ
（サクラ）あっ
That jerk Deidara
is doing as he pleases...
（サソリ）デイダラめ
勝手なまねを…
Hey, wait!
待て こら！
All right.
（デイダラ）よし
Naruto!
（カカシ）ナルト！
（カカシ）チッ… ナルトのやつ
やはり止まらないか
I guess Naruto won't stop, will he?
Naruto and I will take care
of the guy outside.
（カカシ）ナルトと俺は
外のヤツをやる
Sakura and Grandmother Chiyo...
you two handle the guy inside.
サクラとチヨバア様は
中のこいつを…
However...
ただし ガイ班が戻ってくるまで
make sure you don't do
anything rash until Team Guy gets back.
くれぐれも
むちゃはしないように
うん 分かった
Got it.
（デイダラ）うん？
フッ あいつも来たのか
He came too, huh...?
Guy, can you hear me?
（カカシ）ガイ 聞こえるか？
The enemy has split up.
We need backup.
敵が二手に分かれた
援護が必要だ
Return immediately.
今すぐ戻ってくれ
（ガイ）ハア…
それが そうもいかんのだ
I don't think we can.
（カカシ）ん…
ハア… 皆
敵のワナに はまった
We've all been caught
in an enemy trap.
Kakashi, give us a little more time.
カカシ もう少し時間をくれ
あっ…
切るぞ
Signing off!
どわーっ！
（ガイ）くっ この動き…
These movements...
We're an even match, huh?
互角か…
I can't believe they look the same,
have the same power
（ネジ）同じ姿 同じ力
使ってくる術まで同じとは…
and even use the same Jutsu...
（テンテン）ええいっ
It's just like fighting our mirror images...
まるで鏡に映った自分と
戦ってるみたい
If it were mirrors,
we only need to break it, but...
鏡なら割れば おしまいですが…
Leaf Hurricane!
木こノ葉は旋風せんぷう！
It doesn't look like
they'll be easily broken.
簡単に割れそうもありませんね
Give Gaara back!
我愛羅を返しやがれ！
（デイダラ）フッ
Looks like...
（カカシ）こりゃあ…
I can't be wasting my time...
チンタラしてられないな
（サソリ）ハア～
I'd heard that you'd retired long ago.
とっくの昔に引退したと
聞いていたんだがな
I suddenly wanted to see
my grandson's face again.
（チヨ）急に
孫の顔が見たくなってな
（サクラ）はっ
I can tell just by facing him.
対峙しただけで分かる
The incredible difference
in actual battle experience...
ものすごい実戦経験の差と
人を殺してきた数
and the number of people he's killed.
（サクラ）ん…
Sakura, do not fear.
サクラ 恐れるな
I'm here. You step back.
このわしがおる
お前は後ろへ下がっておれ
Assault Blade.
操襲刃そうしゅうは
If you're going to defy me,
then I guess I have no choice...
（サソリ）俺に たてつこうってんなら
しかたねえ
Will you join that kid
そこのガキと 一緒に
俺のコレクションになるか？
as additions to my collection,
Grandma Chiyo?
チヨバアよ
♪～
daitai itsumo doori ni
Just like always.
sono kado wo magareba
As I turn that corner.
hitonami ni magire komi
I am lost in the waves of people.
tokete kiete iku
Melting, disappearing.
boku wa michi wo nakushi
I lose my way.
kotoba suranaku shite shimau
I even completely lose my words.
dakedo hitotsu dake wa
But just one thing.
nokotteta nokotteta
Remained, remained.
kimi no koe ga
Your voice.
warau kao mo okaru kao mo subete
Your smiling faces, your angry faces, everything.
boku wo arukaseru
Keeps me walking on.
kumo ga kireta saki wo mitara kitto nee
Surely, when I see the point where the clouds have broken.
wakaru desho
You know what I mean?
nee wakaru desho
～♪
Next Episode
全国傀儡王選手権
Only one event remains for
the World Puppet Master Championship!
残された競技もあと１つ
栄えある初代 傀儡王に輝くのは
Will the proud title of
first Puppet Master Champion
go to Sasori of the Red Sand,
the master craftsman
第１ステージ 古今東西 毒クイズで
トップ通過を果たした...
who topped the first stage
all-round toxin quiz challenge?!
天才造形師 赤砂のサソリか
はたまた 第２ステージ
傀儡早作り勝負で
Or will it go to Grandma Chiyo,
the Sand's Consultant who displayed
her years of experience and skills
長年の経験と技を見せつけた
砂の相談役 チヨバアか
during the second-stage
Puppet-building race?
最終ステージ 傀儡戦
果たして勝敗は？
Who will win the final stage,
the Puppet Battle?!
Next Time: Hiruko vs Two Kunoichi!
次回「ヒルコＶＳバーサス
二人の女忍者くのいち」
Hiruko vs Two Kunoichi
Guide to the Clans of the Leaf Village:
Volume Two.
（ネジ）木ノ葉 一族図鑑 第２巻
第２巻は うちは一族についてだ
Volume two is about the Uchiha Clan.
This, I'm excited to hear!
（リー）うお～！ それは楽しみです
（ネジ）写輪眼(しゃりんがん)をはじめ
ずば抜けた能力を持つ うちは一族
The Uchiha Clan possesses
outstanding abilities...
...starting with the Sharingan.
There are those in the clan
who specialize in Fire Style techniques.
中でも火遁かとん忍術を得意とし
火を操るうちわを持つ者として
一族の家紋にうちわを用いている
Their clan's symbol is a fan
and represents
those in possession of fans
for controlling fire.
They're the ones who created
the Leaf Police Force
彼らが里の治安を守るために
組織したのが
木ノ葉刑務部隊だ
to protect the safety of the village.
（リー）忍を取り締まる忍
まさにエリートですね
Shinobi who crack down on shinobi.
They truly are the best of the best!
It's said that secrets of the Uchiha Clan
（ネジ）また この南賀ノ(なかの)神社には
are hidden within the Nakano Shrine.
うちは一族の秘密が眠っている
とも言われている
もしかしたら
It might have something to do with
why Itachi and Sasuke left the village.
イタチやサスケの里抜けとも
何か関係があるかもしれないな
It seems there are still many mysteries
to the Uchiha.
うちはには
まだまだ謎が多いですね
In any event, in order to fight against
Itachi's Akatsuki as well as Orochimaru,
いずれにせよ イタチのいる暁あかつきや
大蛇丸おろちまるとやりあうために
we have to get much stronger
than we are now.
俺たちは今以上に
強くならなければならない
In order to do that--!
（ネジ）そのために…
（リー）そのためにも
In order to do that,
we must start with training!
まずは修業です
おい リー 何をする？
Hey, Lee! What're you doing?
— Here we go.
— Put me down!
（リー）いきますよ～
（ネジ）あっ おろせって
Youth Tower Dash!
（リー）青春パワー…
（ネジ）
青春って暑苦しい
Youth is so irritating~!